Viresh Navtake

WEB DEVELOPER | DATA ANALYST

vireshnavtake.cloud@gmail.com

+91 727 6033 480

in viresh navtake

VTP belair, Mahalunge, Pune - 410501

ABOUT ME

I am pursuing my B.Tech in Computer Science with a specialization in Artificial Intelligence. Currently, I'm in my third year. For the past two years, I have been deeply involved in Python, along with its libraries important for data science and machine learning. I have completed two internships as a Data Analyst. Recently, I have expanded my skill set to include front-end technologies. My goal is to pursue a career as a Full Stack Web Developer, also focusing on data science and machine learning

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Artificial Intelligence and Coding Club, Pune — Technical Team Lead

June 2023 - Present

- I joined this club as a member of the technical team and was later promoted to lead.
- Currently, I am leading a team to develop our club's website.

Data Smith, Pune — Data Analyst Intern (on-site)

May 2024 - July 2024

• Trained a machine learning model that predicts the prices of houses based on their type, locality, past inflation in that locality, etc. Learned how to clean, process, and use large datasets.

MTE, New Delhi — Trainee Data Analyst (remote)

July 2023 - Sept 2023

• Worked on the death age ratio analysis project and gained knowledge about the whole lifecycle of data and its features.

HARD SKILL

- · Programming Languages Python, R
- Markup Language HTML, CSS
- Web-based repositories GitHub
- Database MYSQL, PostgreSQL
- OS Linux, Mac, Windows
- Libraries Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Scikit Learn.
- Visulization Tool R Studio
- Data Processing Cleaning, Analysing, Preparing, Feature Engineering, EDA, etc.
- Google Cloud Platform Networking, Infrastructure
- · Machine Learning

SOFT SKILL

- Problem Solving solved 400+ questions (easy to moderate level)
- Interpersonal Communication

AWARDS AND CERTIFICATIONS

Certification

- Google Data Analytics Advanced Coursera
- Python For Data Science and ML Udemy
- Full Stack Web-development Udemy

Awards

- Letter of Recommendation HR team, MTE
- Letter of Appreciation HR team, MTE

EDUCATION

G.H. Raisoni College of Engineering, Pune

bachelor of technology - Computer Science (AI) Nov 2022 - present

Rajarshi Shahu Mahavidyalaya, Latur

Junior College, HSC - 69%, JEE - 83 pth June 2020 - Apr 2022

Yashwant Vidhyalaya, Ahmedpur

SSC - 96%

June 2008 - March 2020